Well, let's move on. As we move on to
the next discussion, we all know the
insurance industry is witnessing a very
powerful and a major shift from friends
simply settling the claims to delivering
a proactive care and approach and of
course a seamless customer digital
experiences. Recent studies also show
that 90% of insurers globally are now
integrating AI into claims workflows
enabling faster decision making
approaching customer efficiency at the
same time making the operation more and
more efficient daybyday. Well, these
technologies have already helping the
claims to be processing time to be
reducing from 70 to 75%. while lowering
the cost of operations by nearly 30 to
35%.
Well, a remarkable change. At the same
time, innovations like predictive
analytics, automated first choice and
real time fraud detection is making
claim settlement preventing risk
management and also having an approach
with customer centric. Well, today's
conversation is going to be more than
that. It's going to have leader talking
about reimagining the journey from claim
to care. This is where the technology
enables faster for the leaders and also
most importantly for the policy holders.
Let me invite the panel one by one on
the stage.
First and foremost joining this dynamic
panel from claim to care enabling
proactive preventing and digital claims
management is Dr. Rohit Salwan, head of
legal and fraud prevention unit FPU at
Baj Alian's Life Insurance Limited. Can
we have a huge round of applause and
welcome him on stage?
Joining us on the panel is Mr.
Sundeparwal, VP and National Head Health
Claims of Ko Tokyo General Insurance.
Can we have a huge round of applause and
welcome him as well?
May I now invite Mr. Namesh Kanabar, CRO
Zurich Kotak General Insurance. Can we
have a huge round of applause and
welcome him?
Joining this panel is M Nazim Khan, head
of internal control and motor third
party claims ICICI Lombard. Can we have
a huge round of applause and welcome Mr.
Nazim Khan
joining this panel. May I now invite
Sorab Chandra, co-founder and CTO, one
assist. Can we have a huge round of
applause and welcome him?
Well, the moderator for this panel is
Kashor Kanani, CRO Magma General
Insurance Limited.
Well, with this powerful panel, I'm sure
we going to have a great key insights
and perspective to share. Can we have a
huge round of applause
over to Mr. Kashor?
>> Good morning everyone and warm welcome
to the panel here. Uh traditionally
insurance have been viewed as a moment
of truth where basically the settlement
of claim is a point which is a promise
which has to be fulfilled and that was
only the expectation of the customer.
Now this moment has been evolving.
Now customers are not only interested in
the settlement of the claim but but the
entire experience uh the wow experience
which I have to say here. Uh so be it
from the claim settlement at a faster
pace to more interactive approach and a
customercentric approach. That's what's
the expectation of the customer has
been. uh we've seen times uh when when
the expectation of the new generation
the the millennials
have already had their period. Now we
have Zen Z, Zen Y, alpha uh and the
beta. So, so this is a new generation
which we'll be dealing with and we need
to understand these are those types of
uh people who would not come to you for
each and every point but would expect
the insurer to reach them and at a click
of the button the information has to be
available otherwise I lose you lose the
customer.
Uh so with the ST panel uh we have this
topic from moving from the claim to care
where uh with the help of technology
data we see reformation is the entire
claim management journey. Uh so I I
welcome the panel here and would uh
would would like to have like to
understand more what what are we going
to understand how is the customer going
to be benefited through this. So before
we start just a quick disclaimer the
views expressed by the panel here are in
their own personal capacity and need not
necessarily represent the views of the
organization they uh represent.
So, so I have the first question while
while so many
Yeah. So, uh the first question is to
you uh Nimsh uh why do you think that we
need to focus on the element of care? Uh
do you think that this softer approach
is a win-win for the customer and to the
insurer at the same time?
>> Absolutely. has rightly said that this
is a win-win situation for both the
insurer and the customer. Now when we
talk about claims if there's no care
there's no service and there's no
insurance I would say because as Kishor
rightly mentioned when we talk about
insurance or claims it is rightly said
as a moment of truth. So if the
insurance company is not able to deliver
when it matters the most it does not
exist for long right. So from a
sustainability perspective, I think care
is the most important word which will
prevail for a very long time and nothing
is going to replace it. Um I just
remember uh working in a life insurance
company earlier. U I was heading the
claims in that uh company. So my CEO was
very interested in terms of how we
communicate to the customer even the
last decision. Right? So typically what
happens is that when you are making a
claims decision and uh sending a letter
to the customer that here is a check for
you right he said this is not giving me
a connect with the customer right how do
I connect is it just sufficient for you
to send a check and inform him that here
is a claims check that's what matters
ultimately from financial perspective
but where is the connect right so he
asked us to draft a letter which could
actually connect with the emotions of
the customer not just a forwarding
letter saying that here is your check
right. It even mentioned that while we
cannot replace the existence of the
bread winner but here is a check which
will help you to navigate through the
financial loss that you that has
happened to your family. Right? So that
is the kind of thing that we talk about
when it comes to care. Right? When we
talk about life insurance or general
insurance be it health claims or motor
claims or whatever claim it is that is
the point where it matters the most.
Right? So how can a company take care of
its customer? When we talk about the
word care, how does how does a company
take care of the customers, right? It is
basically being connected with the
customer in every stage of the claim.
Right? From the time the claim is logged
in till the claim is paid out, giving
him proper information in terms of what
stage it is, right? When you pay the
claim, it's done. Right? But in case if
even if you're not paying the claim, how
do I explain the customer in terms of
why the claim isn't paid? Right? Because
you're not talking about a customer for
this claim alone, right? You're talking
about the long longevity perspective.
You're talking about from a customer's
pers perspective from a very long time,
right? Insurance, life insurance
specifically are long-term contracts
while health insurance now portability
has come in. So if you do not serve the
customer, he's going to the next shop
for sure, right? So that is where it
matters the most and I'm sure most of
the companies are now looking out for
innovative ways in terms of how they can
take care of the customer in innovative
ways. AI is there, ML is there, lot of
stuff, personal touch can never replace
the care. So in terms of how you
communicate to the customer at all ways
of life, at all stages of claim is I
think matters the most. Right? So that
is something what will even determine uh
the stickiness of the customer to the
company. Right? So if you talk about a
general general insurance company where
you're talking about a health claim or a
motor insurance claim, you're talking
about a long-term connectivity of the
customer. It is not just one year and
the customer moves to the next shop.
You're not talking about that, right?
So, it matters the most in terms of how
you are connecting with the customer.
How are you empathizing with the
customer at all stages of claims? I
think that matters the most. Yeah.
Kasha.
>> So, I think well said uh you know
building connect with the customer and
uh helping them during that moment of
crisis is very important. uh it's more
of the care element which is uh
important nowadays. Uh so with this I
move to the next question uh to Sep. Uh
Sep from the customer lens uh what do
you think are the top pain points and
how can technology help us in resolving
the pain points of the customers.
>> Right. Good afternoon everyone. Thank
you very much for the SinX group for
having me at this panel. Um see from the
customer's point of view the biggest
pain point generally is how much time is
it going to take for my claim to settle
how many documentations documents I need
to submit if there would be different
hassles around uh different documents
being submitted time and again queries
being asked status not available where
exactly is my claim and how long is it
going to take so these are the major
pain points which customer does
generally faces in any claims life cycle
and of course technologies with the help
of mobile applications, AI based
applications and uh OCR and the AI based
solutions which are in place right now
lot of things can be done and if status
is provided to the customer in time
documentations
different integrations with the
different agencies like EKYC not asking
for the customer for the KYC we
digitally do it
documents being asked from the hospitals
directly instead of asking from the
customers. Even IID also insist on the
same thing. So things like that if we
are able to solve through technology
which is help which is currently
happening also and if we can improve
upon and have newer technologies to
improve upon that I think that would
help.
>> Thanks. Uh the next question is uh to
Mr. Nazim uh in today's world everyone
wants things at a click of the button.
So what sort of advancements in the
technology can help in building that wow
experience for the customer?
>> Thanks Kishur. Firstly we must
understand uh in the financial services
world look at look at the financial look
at banks. Where does bank comes in life
of people? Mortgage, very happy moment,
personal loan, going for holiday, you
know, auto loan, new car, new bike.
Everything that a bank touches is in the
good moment. Everything that insurance
touches is in the bad moment or a
distressful moment. fire, earthquake,
volcano, torpedo, earth you know theft,
death, injury, accident these are all
stressful moment in the life of people
right and this is where the patience of
the customer is at the lowest
and that's where you know insurance
company normally you know what what I
heard at tarik tarik it's like paper pay
paper we have so many paper and
unfortunately all the fraudsters are
able to give you all papers. The good
customers will never be able to give you
papers, right? So, he's not experienced.
He's just struggling.
What what what we try and do is let me
let instead of giving a let me tell you
what we try and do.
So, years back we used to handle motor
theft.
Why do we require interest report? We
investigate a case. If I'm convinced, I
shall pay
which customer we did for three months.
Why can't we pay in 3 weeks?
You know, but there are associated
issues. Ultimately, one has to the you
see the problem in our country is India
is one of the highest claim paying
country in the world. Roughly 65 to 70%
claims ratio across industry, you know.
across the globe. We are one of the
highest paying nation in the globe with
one of the lowest trust factor
that is the issue. So what we are trying
to do through uh you know one of the
thing that we are trying to do is if I'm
convinced I will see we are overplaying
technology somewhere when humans also
have to take calls right
look at all the papers that you ask for
a claim
can you reduce those number of papers
and on that overlay technology stack as
you said have you integrated dig locker
customer doesn't have to submit have If
you you know you know uh for example the
the the the other thing that we have now
is the integration of credit scores good
credit score just give him a uh a leeway
boss why can't you give him a green
channel you know and integrate it
through back end
integrated so what we try and do is look
at this third party data sources which
are which are available look at some of
the technology which are for example we
were working with some of the uh uh
people who were at least they claim I
don't know whether it's true or not that
they were uh you know uh the US army
used it in Afghanistan and lot of other
places which was a kind of a detection
model yeah abnormal detection model we
integrated it with our claims and it was
able to give us some result so
integrating some of these technologies
and using that is in the substitute for
kagatch yeah to be able to ensure that
you are able to at least bring down the
life cycle of the claim. A B even if you
deny deny fast. Our problem is we deny
after a period of time. Even if you deny
deny fast and third the amount of fear
that he spoke about and these are all
interllaying topics you know you can't
really segregate a question is if you
have to say no say no with the human
face. So year ago we discovered
you don't have a moral courage to answer
the customer. You leave it to some
chitty
you know you have to have if you're
saying no you have to be convinced then
you will have a moral courage to say no.
So what we did we we we actually made
people to explain to the customer why we
are saying no and we suddenly saw the
escalation in litigation dropping down
litigation coming down as a as a reason
of explaining the customer why am I
saying no a it builds moral fiber
it builds a moral fiber organization up
so you know some of this technology
along with human element is something
that we are trying to encompass of
course is what we say right a journey
has start just started and uh hopefully
there will you know there's miles to go
but that's that's a journey for us as a
company and I hopefully us as an
industry
>> so if I may add kish for what Nazim was
saying the bottom line is empathy
>> so the if you empathize with your
customers with your claimants and
understand the genuine customer and
differentiate a genuine customer with a
fraud customer with the use of
technology of course that is where we
are going to it is going to help
>> uh right also what Nazim mentioned that
you know we are the ones who deal with
the customer at the time of crisis so it
more it becomes more important to have
that empathy so I'll just share a very
small uh you know my real life
experience uh so there was one flight I
had been to Fuket traveling from Fuket
to Bangkok and my flight got cancelled
so I was under the impression insurance
but that actually didn't happen that
way. So uh it was the thigh airway. So
when I reached to the insurance company
they asked me certain questions which
which I said
normal customer.
So they said flight disruption
statement. Why should I get it? You go
and coordinate with the airlines. They
said no we will not coordinate with the
airlines. You have to coordinate with
the airlines. Get the flight disruption
statement or the cancellation statement
then come back to me. and punabiz I'm
still struggling to get that statement
but I'm not getting it and I have
actually left it. So think from the
customer's point of view who may not be
knowing an eye of the insurance uh you
know and we expect them to get you the
documents which actually not is not a
cup of history. So how does that feel?
So this is just a flight cancellation.
It could be an experience of a death or
an accident that point of time that
critical moments we need to be there
with the customer and have that empathy
which you two sep mentioned which is
very important.
Uh yeah anyway I I'll move ahead. So so
I understand there's lot of data which
is involved right? So we've been talking
about the data analytics uh the the bot
IoT blah blah machine learning uh so so
what I uh I see that uh there are
challenges around data collection and
maintenance right so how do you think
sort of this can be taken care of
>> hello yeah good afternoon well see I
think challenges around first of all you
know I'll I'll try not to use the word
AI okay being a techie so how many
people from outside technology in this
Okay. Okay. All right. Great. How many
techies in the room?
>> Yeah. No, there are some people who
always never raise their hands. So, they
see speaking about u you know accuracy
and control of data. I think accuracy
through technology is getting
increasingly better right and uh the the
questions around reading a document
whether it's Aadhaar card or a bill etc.
is increasingly lesser and less aer
challenge. Doctor's prescriptions I
think are still some some time away from
us. But I'll give you an example of you
know when how does accuracy really
matter when a machine comes into a play
and a human. So we have a product called
Hawkeye. Okay. What it does is it
basically the technology to scan the
scan a mobile phone and take a decision
whether the phone is insurable or not.
All right. The data goes back to a
machine learning model, right? And the
decision is relayed back to the customer
in about let's say 60 seconds. Okay? Of
course, there is a champion model and
there is a challenger which is a human
queue. We see that as the data matured,
the claim ratios of the machine learning
model are far far better than that of of
the humans. Okay. So the question of
accuracy in technology I think is is is
part of the course. the challenges.
There was second part to the question
which was around um sorry
>> the automation
how does the automation and data
analytics actually uh help us in
reducing the manual intervention.
>> So automation again I said see it's part
of the course. So automation I'll give
you like an example of a discussion
which I was having with a friend in the
life insurance company. So they have a
vision of can we issue a policy a life
insurance policy to the customer in 30
minutes. Okay. The challenges are that
the advisers who collect customer data
and today the industry continues to
source a lot of uh business through
advisers instead of so there is a
customer data then there are documents
so instead of a KYC document a blank
document would be uploaded so that the
lead login happens all right now what
happens to this kind of a lead coming in
it results in outbound calls to
consumers for policy issuance right you
replace this document identification
with an ML model right and there you are
all right the challenges are taken care
of technology exists I'll continue to
not use the word AI but I think Agentic
is making it really possible and really
fast so the technology is available I
think like my friends over here
mentioned that you layer it with a with
with the right empathy you put in the
right technology make use of edge models
so that the customer or the adviser who
pumps in data does it first time right
if you make the upload you if you tell
the person uploading the document that
the document is correct or not right
there you have kind of you know shifted
the problem solved the problem on the
left side and not waiting for it to go
downstream yeah
>> just just you know taking forward what
sor spoke about
so in our uh in our journey towards the
the health claims we have now the fifth
generation of ML learning model fifth
generation we started the journey 3
years back. So all these ML models are
very hungry for learning and you have to
keep continuously refine keep on adding
new new variables. Uh so we have
currently 27 variables. Yeah. And we are
able to say yes or no to at least 70% of
cash claim within three three and a half
minutes or so.
But you know when we were in uh China
last
last month as a company and and our
people met lot of insurers and we some
of the leading insurers in China versus
27 variables that we have they have
around 500 variables 20 times more
variable look at the kind of data those
Chinese guys have obviously can't
compare China with India you you know we
have we're a different country. Yeah, we
have our own U and especially with the
DPDP coming in kicking in place, uh data
availability and consent will become
much more stringent and will have
increasing constraint. But the the the
point I'm telling you is the 70% getting
uh approved in minutes in group health
is is a factor of what is a factor of
the fifth learning model which comes
into play.
One was rudimentary. Five variables,
10 variables, 27 variables. Now keep on
and variables keeps getting added and
getting deleted depending on the output
it throws and the success ratio it
throws. Ultimately what do you want? You
want the maximum buck for the bank. It
investigate less give more more out
better uh success. Yeah. and be able to
give a quick pass through to the right
claim. Yeah. So the journey has to start
somewhere and the journey is long haul
and the journey is continuous continuous
refinement and we still feel we are in
the you know baby days as far as the
whole uh tax stick is concerned.
>> I think a very valid point made by you
uh Nazim. So when we talk about the data
in terms of the quality of the data
right now at least we have reached some
stage where the data quality is slightly
up to the mark I would say not
completely up to the mark but at least
in terms of the data maturity that we
have I think we are reaching there right
earlier the term was that ego
which was a very popular term garbage in
garbage out right we moved a long
distance from there but I think in terms
of the quality of data the variables
that you talked about I think makes a
lot of sense in terms of having the
right data at the right place to get the
right output. I think we have reached
there to some extent but I think still a
long way to go
>> right. Uh well said. Uh next question is
for you Rohit. Uh so this is for more to
do with the anti- fraud relating thing.
So while there has been a need to move
from fraud detection postevent to early
detection, how effective are the
predictive models in identifying such
potential frauds?
>> Sure. Uh thanks Kisho. Uh so uh so
before I jump into uh the right
questions uh so the the zone of the
discussion is claim uh claim settlement
claim insurance claim and I look a claim
from a very different perspective as my
all colleagues look I look from a uh
claims from a FPU perspective and uh
from a legal perspective. I had both he
and illegal. So it's a long journey for
me when you uh when we talk about a
claim and maybe I look at claim from a
more darker perspective than my
colleagues
my panel colleagues and u we talk about
softer approach we talked about empathy
which is of course it's welcome when we
talk about insurance claim settlement
uh but at the same time we should also
So consider and factor a point that
there is a paral industry which is
called a nexus which is running a you
know a toe to toe a step to step right
in you know right besides us. So we
should also factor that in mind when we
and all those softer approach empathy is
of course the insurance is all about
payment of a claim is not about
reputation that's what the genesis of
insurance
and so so go by that word of course we
should pay a claim and we have as Nim
says we have one of the best claim
settlement ratio across country
um
but of course yeah So so so so from
where I am coming from from a FPU and
from a legal perspective
uh and the factors that I have seen the
more the dark darker factor that I've
seen uh
stop rather than reputation of a claim
at the at a claim stage if we put some
factors some predictive analysis at a
onboarding stage
we understand there is a business
pressure we have to do you know the
business in a in a fraction of minutes
that's how the competition work if I
don't do somebody else will do and
insurance is more of a you know it it
works on a utmost good faith principle
of utmost good faith I need to trust
what customer is saying I and it's not
typically a a financial sector when I
ask so many documents from a customer uh
when underwriting
a typical days. So we we we generally
ask for a basic questions very basic
financial questions very basic
liveliness questions basics mortality
question and basis that we underwrite.
So the point I'm trying to make is if at
the onboarding stage if we'll try to
build up a case or more productive
analysis model where we'll not we'll be
able to filter a cases which is less on
mortality or maybe we'll be able to
onboard a good life so that claims cases
going at a stage of a or maybe I'm
reviewing that case at a post issuance
stage or at a claim stage doesn't work.
So of course every insurance company has
a three line of defense. First is your
preiss insurance when we do it. The
predictive analysis is running there. Of
course there is a business challenges.
So there are not that those
uh models are not that sharp. So maybe I
have a second line of defense when I
said post issuance. I still can analyze
entire my portfolio at a post issuance
level. I still can weed out the cases. I
can do a uh I do a a cancellation of
cases at so that those cases will not go
into the claim.
But having said that all those first
line of defense, second line of defense
cases reaches to the claim reputation
because
of course there are two way of looking
at it when when when we'll see a claim
reputation. One is customer awareness
from insurance perspective. They doesn't
know what kind of information need to
pass on or maybe a person who's trying
to pitch in a insurance is trying to
doesn't not not been able to educate
them. This is the critical information.
Maybe if you'll give this information
not necessarily you will not get an
insurance but maybe a little you know
high paid up premium you will get it but
you will get a product rather than
making you know ending up buying a
cheaper product and then in the
eventuality god forbid the claim will be
repudiated. So of course whatever
experience we have, whatever industrial
experience we have um and everybody is
working on a red flag segments all those
needs to be put into place and uh
those things basically we need to uh put
in place while we are working on our uh
underwriting tools or maybe our FP
we call it as an FRE rule. engines which
needs to be run at both stages maybe at
a pre-issuance also post is insurance
also and uh of course that's could be a
reason where we can reduce a you know
burden at a claim processing also
because the lesser cases will come at a
claim stages there is a team which is
working claim team is working a legal
team is working on that to give an
decision on that and every reputation
case may be you know some kind of a
learning that we need some kind of
experience that we need to build in and
we need to sharpen our predictive
engines also so that you know
decisioning will be fast. It will be a
customer very good customer experience
for uh for good c customer experience
also uh because it's better to say no at
a sales of a onboarding that's saying a
no at a claim stage because of course
somebody is taking insurance so somebody
is trying to invol a
kind of a eventuality
which may come in the and he may require
that kind of a claim so I'm talking from
a life insurance perspective. Of course,
general have a more complicated kind of
a fabric to work with. Yeah, that's from
my side. Thank you.
>> Thanks. Uh Rohit Nazim, since you have
also been handling the anti-fraud unit
uh and have vast experience, what are
the uh challenges with respect to the
fraud analytics? Uh where do you see it
going?
>> Look, uh you know, we can talk about
fraud till cows come home. Uh
look at banking space. What happened to
the banking space? I started my career
in the '90s. Yeah. Mid '90s.
Borrower used to borrow from NBFC,
Kotak, go to Sundaram, go to
Chulamandlum, go to Apple, go to City
Bank, go to Stan Cy, go to XY Z. So
there was no credit scores, right? It
was a free-for-all.
as a consequence delinquencies
please slightly
you're disturbing my thoughts so people
used to borrow from XY Z and the
delinquencies were high and ultimately
who paid for the delinquencies other
customers right good customers pay for
the bad customers now let's look at the
insurance
and over a period of time from '90s 2007
the sik act came in then the credit
bureaus came in for for credit bureaus
and and today the look at look at what
is banking is by and large having a
control people all of you I'm sure look
at your credit score right and all of
your conscience and all of your
conscience you want your credit score to
be high 750 it should become 775 it
should become 800 that's that's that's
what you are now look at what's
happening in insurance who has a there's
one thing that we really wanted to drive
as an industry. How do we get in the the
individual credit rating for insurance
either as a integrated part of the
credit score? Yeah. Uh of a holistic
credit score or on a standalone basis
and that's what we we were trying to
press with the regulator impress upon we
made couple of some presentations we
also tried on a loan. For us, I think
the biggest biggest game changer will be
when we bring
distributor
I will be out of distribution business.
Hospital I will be never impelled by
anybody else.
Auto garage will feel that insurance
business will be out from them. the
whole ecosystem till such time that
doesn't realize we'll work on
transactions
and for that to happen we need to
collectively work as an industry with
the regulator and and then when that
happens that that that will completely
change the way we are doing that will
bring down the cost it will bring down
the friction uh before we came here we
were discussing why UP has taken up
taken up because there's No friction.
Just pick up your phone and if a
transaction happens
claims friction,
fraud, anti-section, waste, abuse
by various people by the whole chain
starting from sourcing to servicing to
distribution to post sales to claims to
claim servicing people to surveyors to
investigators
to the to the service providers all can
become a part of the fraud risk.
It it's just not one claimment right
it's not one customer the customer one
customer in isolation can do nothing
the whole valuation comes it's it's a
collusion and you know uh and and for
that collision to disappear systemic
level changes is something otherwise
we'll keep on doing some analytics doing
some transaction basis
every claim should be paid
this is the mantra that we have
Now for every claim to be paid what
should happen right and writing a fear
look at today look at the historical low
in banking today if you're getting auto
loan at 8 and a half% you must thank
credit rating otherwise everybody will
have been paying 10%. And that 1 and a
half% should have been for bad
customers.
Yeah.
>> Uh well said. I think it's the entire
system ecosystem has to work together to
ensure to get that seamless experience
for the customer. Uh Nimsh uh while
we've been talking about the AI so
what's the role of human oversight uh
over this particular piece?
So when we talk about AI you cannot
replace a human oversight for sure
right. So when we talk about now each
and every company is using AI ML in some
form or the other right but imagine one
thing that it is a continuous learning
process so it cannot be that claims
decisions are happening without human
oversight right so typically if I talk
about high value claims right now
imagine claims being decided just by AI
right now what is the role of human in
that right it could be that you are
paying a claim which is not payable or
otherwise right in case If you end up
not paying a claim which is payable, it
could be a huge reputational loss for
the company. Right? So I cannot imagine
a
state where uh even if AI is there you
have got the best of the models where
you got the best of ML data fed in and
it is giving you results at best it is
an aid to decision making right
definitely AI has helped because before
the decision making lot of things which
were earlier laborious to make right in
terms of the basic things are put in
place right so you don't have to waste
your mind in terms of the basics right
or in terms of at least giving you
direction in which the claims decision
is ultimately going. But if I talk about
human oversight definitely cannot be
replaced especially for high value
claims. If you talk about very low low
value claims maybe to some extent yes
the auto decision-m may work but again
it requires a lot of sampling a lot of
audit in terms of how the AI is
operating for you in terms of decision
making. So definitely human oversight
cannot be replaced even you have the
best of AI.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I just wanted to come in
here and ask you know we whenever we
talk about decisioning and human
oversight we inadvertently move towards
claims but what about sourcing see the
Nazim was talking about industry
expansion right that the industry is not
expanding the insurance company same set
of insurance insurance companies are
competing for a limited set of customers
right but when it when you look at
sourcing if you put you know I I know I
said I will not use the word AI but now
the technology and AI is available where
in a governed an autonomous way you can
actually source cases at scale and
therefore put efforts in expanding the
boundaries of the industry. So so why is
the question of decisioning always
coming to or or the human element always
coming to claims only and why is there
no thoughts around expanding the market?
>> Yeah, absolutely. I think a lot of work
has happened in terms of expanding the
market beyond claims as well. Right. So
we are no longer talking about uh in
terms of decision- making through AI
only for claims. Definitely not. So
Nazim also rightly spoke that when it
comes to banking sector at least you
have a credit score which gives you a
direct reflection in terms of what the
customer is made all about right in
insurance we are not having that but in
terms of insurance also as you rightly
said sourcing is a big area I think
where AI ML can help in terms of
onboarding the right customer right
because are we onboarding the right
customer because it ensures the thought
processes that premium given and policy
cut out that's not the case anymore
right so definitely AI is helping in a
long way in terms of onboarding the
right customers also. So it's no longer
just restricted to claims but it's also
helping in onboarding the right
customer. uh interesting sort of for
example 50% of two wheelers in India is
uninsured after the primary insurance
roughly roughly now the question is
will the profitability of the industry
and the price for the customer come down
if everything was insured
theoretically speaking
key claim happens on hit and run cases
and a insured vehicle is implanted right
so the People who are insured are
bearing for people who are not insured.
Prices are high.
Can you the the whole challenge for us
is at a scale. See today the cost of
distribution is very high. Therefore the
penetration is not going up in KD CAT E
towns. Yeah. You go to Gojhati but can
you go to Morao? Can you go to beyond
Morau? Can you go to Kad D? You go to
Nasi but can you go to Sar? Can you go
to uh Neif Neif
you know can you go to all those towns
and kind of then the economies so where
where he's talking about is and it
really help the penetration will help
the loss cost for the industry and will
really kind of you know and on a on a
larger base you can accommodate
uh you know uh uh uh much better is
something which which you know but BM
That's one one uh uh thing that we have
not been able to crack as an industry.
There's a big big bane 50% uninsured
vehicle especially two-heer and maybe 35
40% of uh non non-toer you know
passenger cars and what not being
insured is a huge huge uh issue for us
here.
>> I'll just add to uh what Nazim also
said. So Nazim as you rightly said just
in the previous question that uh many of
the cashless claims are being decided in
a matter of minutes right definitely
it's a big boon because had it not been
AI this would not have been possible so
definitely a very big boon so I remember
the good old days when AI was not there
I remember we had developed a model on
Excel right which used to give us kind
of a score in terms of uh determining
whether or not to onboard this customer
or what do we do additionally to onboard
the customer do I do a backend and check
do I ask him to go for a medical check.
So those days also there were models but
now definitely as you also rightly said
for sourcing definitely AI is a bone big
bone but when it comes to claims
definitely some human oversight I
wouldn't rule out just I don't want to
memorize this but just one one quick you
know I was speaking somebody with Amazon
a friend of mine
90 days
and he was part of our industry before
and then he kind of migrated to a
different industry. It got so AI is a b
implementation is talk is this first
issue second so much biases AI has so
many biases human being have biases
right cars creed color sex gender etc
etc AI has also so many biases and over
a period of time biases scripts in you
don't even know when biases scripts in
the second thing is what about cost AI
is not cheap
The cost of AI is also something
sometimes traditional methodology is
cheap is is so we'll have to you know
really on a on a on a on a continuum
look at all these elements yeah cost
biases benefits human overlay over AI
and look at it holistically and not get
carried away by by this word any
conference you go
that is the Uh but Nim might differ with
you but we'll discuss this offline.
>> We get to hear various different
interest.
>> I just wanted to ask last question you
went with your family to Bangkok.
>> I will answer that separately out of
syllabus.
Uh okay in the interest of time probably
I'll try to wrap up or could be the last
questions for you Sep. Uh what will
differentiate best-in-class claim
organization over the next 3 to 5 years?
Will it be the technology, data, culture
or what would you think would be the
best answer here?
>> See, basically it is going to be a
combination of all and we are talking
about so many pain points, so many other
things AI and other aspects from the
customer point of view for a health
claim even today a customer is
discharged in the morning. The doctor
says you are you are ready to go to home
and practically the patient goes in the
evening.
It is it is not about whether the
insurance company is able to do it in
minutes. It is about the entire cycle
itself. The hospital is taking a lot of
time. The other parties involved in the
process they are also taking their own
time. So are we looking at some
technology based solutions to work for
solution for entire cycle instead of
looking at the pieces of say
specifically from the insurance company
point of view or only from the customer
point of view or from the hospital point
of view. So sorry to digress I was just
thinking on that. So Sarab is is there
anything where we are also from
technology standpoint that AI is helping
on reducing that time which is a pain
point for the customer. Yeah, you know,
I can totally relate to this uh to this.
My mother had a catact operation and
post procedure I was told she had to
wait for 4 hours because the claim
settlement will take so much of time.
Right? I had to
>> insurance company would claim that we
have settled within 5 minutes.
>> This is I'm talking about the medic
claim which mean it was already a
company policy. Can you imagine? Right?
So I had to eventually leave my card
over there and said you charge on this
and the claim comes you reverse it. So
the point is that there is a team of
doctors who sitting there verifying all
the documents right and then I was
talking to a good friend of mine in the
healthcare industry that we need to
really solve for this right you can't
expect a a 60 plus old woman right who's
just undergone a procedure to wait for
four to five hours over there right so
Nazim doesn't agree but the biases can
be solved using AI and these problems
can be solved yeah
>> we should discuss this
>> so that's where technology as well as
the human intervention because the
persons who are working on the desk
creating a discharge summary submitting
documents and then the flow of those
documents to the insurance companies and
then insurance company again there are
people working and use of technology in
analyzing the claim and analyzing
>> nobody's happy the hospital is not happy
that the patient is sitting the patient
definitely is not happy I am agrieved
the whole ecosystem everybody's unhappy
>> and on top of it you have to also check
as he also said and Nazim was also
referring the element of fraud that 5 to
7% % of fraudsters which is affecting
the balanced 90 95% of the genuine
customers is where that differentiation
factor has to be there.
>> I didn't I have nothing against AI. I'm
saying we must just be careful in terms
of cost and biases. That's the only
point that I'm otherwise I'm all for AI.
>> Wow. I I think it was a great experience
learning from the experts uh how how
this journey transformation journey from
claims to care has been. Uh so uh I I
think we are right on time and the floor
is open for questions if any from the
audience.
Yeah, there are there are awards for
this is it there are there are awards
for questions.
Yeah, please.
No questions.
>> Uh, okay.
>> The mic's not working for the
>> Yeah,
yes, please.
Hi. Hi. Yeah. Few things still need
human intervention. Yeah. So, my name is
Dhiraj. My question is to uh Nazim sir.
So, uh with the help of uh the data uh
analytics and the technology and the
digital uh capabilities in the insurance
se uh sector. Uh do you uh see any
changes from uh a perspective change
from paying claim to preventing
prevention of claim specifically in the
third party uh insurance uh in in motor
insurance
third party if the only way to prevent a
claim is prevent accident happening
right claim arises when an accident
happens how do you prevent Mr. Mr. Gakar
is struggling for last 10 years to
prevent accident happening and every
year unfortunately we see one lakh
75,000 Indians dying on the roads. We
have we have been a signary to the uh
2020 Geneva convention where we thought
that in 2015 we agreed to bring down the
death by 50%. We had in 2026 we have
shifted that milestone to 2030.
You know how do you reduce? So in
isolation you can't do anything right
but
So I'll tell you what we have done you
know
we have adapted certain routes along
there's a NGO called safe way yeah and
uh safe roads and we are working with
them so we have we have adopted the
Bombay Pune highway what we have done is
uh uh and there are few stretches where
we have ensured why does an accident
happen because of engineering because of
driving habits because of you know uh
drunk driving, slipping, so many complex
reasons right why when motor accident
happens uh on a stretch of a road uh
which is about 50 km we have kind of
ensured that we'll fix the these these
parts accident you realize suddenly that
the there was a engineering issue in the
road and there was people the the
traffic used to merge all you need to do
was put some engineering on the road
some dividers operators coloring and
some human uh for a few period of time
that NGO started we we did it as a CSR
that that's that it was implementing
agency on a stretch of roads we were
able to bring down at least his claim is
that we were able to bring down the
accident by 75% on that stretch of 50 km
over a bit of one year's calendar year
24 25 bring down
So insurance company can use some of the
CSR that it has. If you're especially if
you're a motor insurance company, if
you're also into motor insurance, it is
a natural fit for you, right? To be able
to or on the on the health side, what is
preventive? Preventive is you know
towards SEP G will kind of agree that
claim foreign bad you know 10 12% people
do a recurring claim. So what is it when
the moment a claim comes can you uh do
you know preventive uh so there are
agencies now who are doing a preventive
work so that a reoccurrence doesn't
happen third is in in in China what do
they say the doctor is paid not for
treatment but for keeping you away right
can insurance company say
so for that to happen what is happening
is is the OPD on the All preventive
this
look look at motor flood if there is a
forecast of heavy rains in Hyderabad
what do you do you do send alerts to the
all the motorist you also have latitude
longitude you know over a period of time
con Bangalore may what are the lowlying
areas you know you also know what are
the affluent pin codes which will have
BMW which will have merc and a
combination of data analytics AI weather
forecasting will tell do preventive work
that can happen with a set of policy
holder in that focused area
but you know you do some of this thing
but this is just not enough these are
all good example to show on the
powerpoint slide right
but as as a industry I think the
question is very good how do you move as
an industry from a mindset of a of a
reactive to a proactive where a
mitigation to prevention risk management
in the in the corporate space
you know when we do our whole approach
is how to prevent a fire happening is
not not to insure because now we are
dealing with 5,000 corporates and we
have done fire insurance for them
what are the preventive he doesn't have
that theme owner doesn't have the
experience how do I do control
engineering how do I do loss
minimization at that point in time So
the whole industry I think as an
industry we need to competition
collaboration
well for business we can compete but for
some of these prevent area because this
is a win-win for the country for the
citizens of this India. Great question
sir.
>> Thank you. Thank you sir.
>> Uh thank you. In the interest of time we
can take one more question. Uh last
question
anyone?
Yes, gentlemen there.
Uh my question to Nime sir uh you know
we are talking about the AI what about
the s moral had because we have seen uh
many dealers uh because I'm the motor
and writing team so I'm just talking
about the motor related things so many
you know especially I'm just giving a
example that in the western UP there are
many dealers where moral hazard is very
high so how we can control through AI
because we cannot control through AI
because there's
They create very genuine claims they
create it. You will go there for the you
know workshop for the just servicing
they will create a you know claims and
convert into the claims. So if you'll
see that there is a claim ratio is very
high. So is there any AI involved or it
would be totally MI only?
>> Okay great question. So as I mentioned
uh in our conversation also that AI is
definitely a big aid in terms of the
final decision making right but exactly
what you mentioned there's a element of
moral hazard also that's where human
intelligence comes to play right so
human intelligence has to top up on the
AI I would call that AI is a student and
human is a teacher right so it's a
teacher student relationship so for
typically as you rightly said human mind
works faster than AI at times right? You
have an AI in place and there's some
human who is trying to work on the
loopholes in terms of how he can uh
combat the AI as well. So that's where
human intelligence comes to play and
that's where you need to have some audit
in place some other triggers in place
how you can combat things. So AI is only
going to give you an aid in terms of
what could be the right steps in that
direction but definitely human element
is required for such cases.
Second question.
>> Can I Hello. Uh can I ask a second
question to Sep? Uh sir uh normally we
take sir lots of decision we works on
the AI but when we take a actual action
then there is a team we call
distribution channel. They come to us
and they says that we have to pay
otherwise there will be loss of the
premium loss of the relationship and
all. How we can manage through claims
and distribution both? See that's what
we earlier also this was talked about
there are business challenges of course
procuring business is important for any
organization top line is where unless
you have a business you cannot settle a
claim if you do not have a business the
finding out the right business and using
AI based technology in procurement and
identifying the customer. You talked
about moral hazard. Moral hazard you
cannot judge by AI. This has to be done
through various documentations, various
papers submitted by the customer, the
profile of the customer and judging it
with the data. So that business would
definitely remain and that friction of
underwriting versus claims or marketing
versus claims would always remain.
>> Thank you sir. Thanks a lot.
>> Uh Mr. Nadim. Yeah. Hi.
My leading question to your your
judgment was you did a a survey on that
Puna Puna Mumbai stretch road for 50 km
or something. So my question was yeah my
question can you hear me? My question
was claim
>> obviously
outside fraud you know forget a fraud
part of it claim will be a function of
accident right the ultimate objective of
that project was not selfish to get less
claim it was more out of good spirit
less human beings shall die on the road
yeah that was the objective the sweet
part of It is
part of it.
Ultimately
there has to be life beyond claim also.
We are all human beings.
We have to broaden but
if your intention is right the result
will follow. Your intention is to reduce
human
uh loss, reduce accident, user fatality.
If that happens, automatically claim
will will be uh will reduce
automatically reduce
75%
unless there increase in fraud.
And the second question was
AI will only so what we do is simulate.
So for what we do for example every
accident that happens for example
30 seconds
30 seconds. So for every accident that
happens we capture attributes right.
Paka road, Pakar road, national highway,
state highway, latitude, longitude, tar
road, cement road, you know
near school, near liquor shop, near p
you know gi kenda, bhar left, right, all
these attributes and 100 others are
captured in a claim and then you try and
analyze excellent work
but that that is only for your set of
customers you we only have 10% market
share right 90% % market share is
outside us
right we don't have 100% market share I
can only do it for for my uh this and so
but with the limited experience that you
have you're able to figure out
you know village village road is merging
into this people have to take a U-turn
you know people from crossing from east
of the village to the west of village
has to cross this where there's no
barricading so you you when you start
doing this 10% you you start getting
answer and you then assume what is true
for me is true for what is true for
goose is true for gander right what is
true for us is true for kotak is true
for chola etc etc and then you you work
with those people with the nos and say
issue or
expert
and then you were able to kind of put
those mitigation plan in place.
>> I'm sure Dr. Kay would have more
questions to add but I think
can speak at length. So, so I think uh
we are at the end of the session and we
can close it. Uh thank you. Thanks
everyone.
>> Fabulous. With this panel I think we all
know the future of claim management is
just no longer about only reimbursement.
And it is more about anticipation, you
know, care and of course uh prevention.
Thank you so much. What a fabulous. I
think we could have go on and on and the
questions and the way you articulated
it, it was fabulous. Can we have a huge
round of applause for all the leaders
I felt like you all were talking but you
know it was very interactive. It was
like something that we always look
forward to. Well, let's get going. Um
now may I now invite uh Mr. Krishnan
Menan senior specialist adviser business
development entity data information
processing services private limited on
stage can we have a huge round of
applause for him first and foremost from
the panel I request Dr. Rohit Salwan,
head of legal and fraud prevention unit,
Bajage Life Insurance Limited to join us
on center stage and accept the momentto.
Thank you so much for joining in.
Can we have a huge round of applause
everybody?
I may now request Sundi Bagarval, VPN
national head health claims of Ko Tokyo
General Insurance. Can we have a huge
round of applause? Once again a very
great insights from all the leaders out
here.
I may now call upon Nimsh Kabar CRO
Zurich Kotuk General Insurance. Thank
you once again sir for sharing key
insights.
May I now call upon Mr. Nazim Khan, head
of internal control and motor third
party claims ICIC Lombard. First of all,
a thank you sir and thank you for making
it so interactive and interesting. Can
we have a huge round of applause for
him?
May I now call upon Mr. Surab Chandra,
co-founder and CTO, one assist. Once
again, a huge round of applause. Thank
you so much for the constructive key
point highlighters.
Yes, the captain of the ship like I
finally say and the moderator for this
fantabulous panel Kish Khan Chandarani
CRO Magma General Insurance Limited.
Thank you. And with all the momentos
I'll request you to please join us on
the center stage for a group picture all
of you. Yes sir. With the momentos
please.
Well, uh with AI, projective analytics
and digital platform transforming uh the
ecosystem, insurers have the opportunity
to move from reactive claim settlement
to proactive customer protection and
seamless care delivery. And thank you
for highlighting this. Can we have a
fabulous round of applause for such an
interactive panel?